asdapriceguarantee.co.uk 2018-02-18

# Privacy Policy | ASDA

## Our Privacy Mission Statement:

> "At ASDA, we value the trust placed in us by customers, suppliers and colleagues who give us their personal data. Data security is one of our highest priorities and we aim to be as clear as possible about what we do with personal data and why we do it." 

## Our Privacy Statement for ASDA websites

Your privacy is really important to us, and we understand how important it is to you. Our aim is to be as clear and open as possible about what we do and why we do it. ASDA is committed to the online privacy of all its users. 

This Privacy Policy regulates the use by ASDA and its partner companies of the information you provide when using ASDA websites. 

This ASDA website is run by the ASDA group of companies and its partners (" **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** ") 

We run this site in order to promote products and services and, where these are provided by our partners, to be the link between our customers and our partners. Our partners may have their own privacy policies which you should also look at. 

## Information We Collect

To be able to order from us we have to collect certain information from you. As part of this, you are required to give your contact information. We use the information given to us by you to provide the service you request from us in the way that is set out in this privacy policy. You can change your registration details easily through the account facilities available on the website or by getting in touch with our Data Protection Officer at the address below. 

**User name and password** \- if we collect a user name and password, this is so we can keep your information safe and so that we can have your information to hand each time you visit us. 

**Name, address and postcode** \- without this we won't know where to send your order or to whom. We also use postcodes to quickly get your full address to save you typing it out, and in some cases to identify whether we deliver or offer services in your area. 

**Age / date of birth** \- we may need to collect your age or date of birth in order to be able to sell you certain products, such as insurance, financial services products or alcohol, and we may also use this to send you age or birthday related offers if you have agreed to receive marketing communications. 

**Email address** \- we send a confirmation of your orders via email as well as other service related communication. If you have agreed to receive marketing communications these may also be sent by email. 

**Telephone numbers** \- if there are any problems with your order or we need to check anything, we need to be able to contact you quickly. 

**Payment card number, expiry date, issue no and name of card holder** – A payment card is required in order to register for an online account. We retain your payment card information for the duration of the time you hold an account with us. This is necessary to enable payment, to process refunds and in order to help us monitor fraudulent activity on accounts. 

**Where you heard about us** \- we may ask you this to help make our marketing more efficient. 

**Correspondence** \- if you contact us we may keep a record of that correspondence. 

**Sensitive personal data** \- sensitive personal data includes, for example, information related to your health, race or ethnic origin or religion. We may need sensitive personal data from you for certain products and services, and in some cases, we may be able to assume sensitive personal data about you from the information you provide. By letting us have any sensitive personal data, you expressly consent to us using and telling others about any of your sensitive personal data so we can provide you with the goods or services requested by you in the way set out in this Privacy Policy. 

**Third party information** \- if you give us information about another person, (for example if someone else is taking delivery for you or is included in the purchase of a product) you confirm that you have identified ASDA to them and told them what we will use their information for, as set out in this Privacy Policy and that they have given permission for us to be able to use their personal information in the manner described. 

**IP addresses** \- when you visit our site, we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device. 

**ASDA Money** \- We work with third parties to provide you with our ASDA Money products and services. These parties, our partners, help us by running our various ASDA Money websites and collecting your information to be able to provide you with quotes, information, and with the products and services you purchase.   
Where you submit information on an ASDA Money website, our partners will collect this information and use it to provide you with the information requested, such as your quote, and then if you purchase a product or service our partner will use that information to administer that product or service for you. Their privacy policy will apply to their use of your information, and you will be able to able to find it on their website or in the product information. Our partner will also provide your information to us and we will use your information in accordance with this privacy policy, and where you have consented will use this information as set out below in the marketing section. 

You may also provide us with personal information if you contact customer services, if you enter promotions or competitions run by us or if you get in touch with us in some other way, for example by way of an email facility provided on the website. 

## How We Use The Information We Collect

Our main uses of your information are explained above which in general is to process your orders, as well as to help us understand your needs and provide you with a better service.   
Your account may be used to store information about your previous purchases, personal preferences and shopping lists. But you should also be aware of the following uses -

**Marketing** \- we (including our group companies and partners) and carefully selected third parties may use the information we collect to inform you, by letter, phone, SMS, push notification or equivalent, or email, about offers, products and services that we think may be of interest to you and we may tell you about other organisations' products and services. 

We will tell you about this when we collect your information and if you do not wish to receive these communications, please let us know. You can change your mind at any time by going to the account facilities available on the website or by contacting our Data Protection Officer at the address below. You can also unsubscribe following the instructions that we will include in any communication, such as email or text, we send to you.

**Customer care and correspondence** \- as part of our customer care procedures, we may follow-up, either by letter, phone, SMS or email, customers who have purchased goods or services from our website or who have posted comments about ASDA on the internet, for example to resolve a complaint or to ask for a testimonial. 

**Market research** \- from time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by letter, phone, SMS or email. 

**Personalise shopping** \- we may personalise your experience by using your past purchases and browsing habits to present special offers and new products and services that we think may be of interest to you. As technology develops this will really help us to improve our service to you. 

**Website improvement** \- to help us design our website and improve your experience, we may collect information about the way you use and access our website. Our web system collects information about each visitor, including IP address, the length of time spent on the website and the order in which pages are visited. We may employ third party experts to help us look at this information. However, we make sure that anyone we employ treats all information with the same sensitivity and security that we treat it. This is explained in more detail in the cookies section below. 

**Fraud Prevention** \- in order to protect our customers and us from fraud and theft, we may look at the information that we get from making identity checks and other information in our customer records, including how you conduct your account, and may pass this to other group companies, other retailers and to financial and other organisations (including law enforcement agencies) involved in fraud prevention and detection, to use in the same way. 

When you apply for products or services through our website you may also be required to go through a more detailed credit check on terms which will tell you about you first.

## Cookies

Our sites use a number of different cookies. Below we explain the cookies we use and why we use them.   
What is a cookie?   
Cookies we use and why we use them   
Your right to refuse cookies and what happens if you refuse them

**What is a cookie?**   
A cookie is a small text file that may be placed on your device when you visit our sites. When you next visit our sites the cookie allows us to distinguish you from other users.

**There are two broad categories of cookies:**

  1. **Persistent cookies**   
Persistent cookies remain on your device until deleted manually or automatically. 
  2. **Session cookies**   
Session cookies remain on your device until you close your browser when they are automatically deleted. 

**Cookies we use and why we use them**

  1. **Essential cookies**   
Essential cookies are technical cookies that are required for the operation of our sites. Without essential cookies our sites can’t operate properly. Essential cookies include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas. 
  2. **Performance cookies**   
Performance cookies allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors to our sites and to see how visitors move around them. This helps us to improve the way our sites work by enabling us to tailor our sites to the way visitors use them. The information we collect from performance cookies is aggregated which means that we cannot identify you from it. 
  3. **Experience cookies**   
Experience cookies allow our sites to remember the choices you make. Our sites use experience cookies to provide you with enhanced and personalised features. For example, we use information collected through what are known as “web-analytic” cookies to compare the choices you make to those of our other customers so that we can learn from those choices.   
Information collected by experience cookies cannot track your browsing activity when you leave our sites to browse other sites. 
  4. **Marketing cookies**   
Marketing cookies record your visits to our sites, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We use this information to make our sites and the advertising displayed on them more relevant to your interests. For example sometimes we use marketing cookies to limit the number of times that you see an advert. Sometimes we share information about your browsing activity, (which we have collected from cookies), with our advertising partners. They may use this information to advertise products, which may interest you, on other sites. 

**Your right to refuse cookies and what happens if you refuse them**   
You can refuse cookies by activating the relevant setting on your browser. However, if you do so you may not be able to access all or parts of our sites. If you carry on using our sites and do not change your browser settings we will assume you consent to us using cookies as described above.

## Access Rights

You have a right to access the personal information that is held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information ASDA holds about you, please email us at [dataprotection@asda.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@asda.co.uk) enclosing your postal details and the details of your request.   
Alternatively you can write to us at the following address:   
Data Protection Officer,   
Privacy Compliance,   
ASDA Stores Limited,   
ASDA House,   
Great Wilson Street,   
Southbank,   
Leeds, LS11 5AD 

**Security** \- at ASDA, information security is very important and we have taken many steps to make sure your shopping experience with us is secure. Information about you will be kept safe and secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure of your information, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect and secure information that is collected online. 

**Keeping your information secure** \- to help us keep your information confidential you should: 

  1. Keep your password secret.
  2. Never distribute the website addresses for pages that you have looked at while logged in as a registered customer.

**Password** \- you should choose a password that is not obvious or known to anyone else. You should never give a third party your password, as you will be responsible for all activity and charges incurred through use of your password whether authorised by you or not. 

If you forget your password, you can request a new password, which will be emailed to the address we hold for you. You can change your password anytime through the account facilities on the website. Should we think that there is likely to be, or has been any breach of security, we may change your password and notify you of the change by email. 

**Payment Card Security** \- we use Verisign and the latest SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) technology to make sure that the details you provide when placing an order are kept private and secure, making shopping on our website safe. Our secure server encrypts your credit or debit card number details along with your personal information and changes them into bits of code that are then securely sent over the internet. Your browser will show when you are in a secure environment by displaying either a locked padlock or an image of a key in the grey bar at the bottom of the page; it may also warn you when you are entering a secured environment as you go to place your order. Once your payment information is received by us, your payment card is processed through the same systems that handle our store sales - so they're tried and tested over many years of secure operation. 

**Security in our offices** \- access to your information is restricted in our stores and offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. The servers that store this information are kept in a secure environment. 

**Purchase Guarantee** \- we are so confident about security on our website that when you shop with us we back each of your credit card purchases with a guarantee. In the unlikely event that unauthorised use is made of your credit card, most card issuers either cover all the charges that result from the unauthorised use or may limit your liability to £50. If your credit card issuer holds you liable for any of this £50 we will reimburse you up to the full £50. This guarantee applies where the unauthorised use is as a direct result of giving us your credit card details on our secure server and not through your own fault. 

## Mobile Applications

ASDA's mobile applications may include functionality to allow you to create a shopping list, search or add products to a favourites list using voice input or text, or by scanning bar codes, check price or product availability and print coupons, browse, search and buy ASDA.com products, locate the nearest ASDA store, track orders, find aisle locations for items on your shopping lists, order prescription refills, and view, share and print your online photos. 

In addition to the information mentioned above, our mobile applications may collect certain information automatically, such as the type of mobile device you use, the temporary or persistent unique device identifiers (sometimes called UDID) placed by us or our service providers, the unique identifier assigned by ASDA to your device, your location, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use our mobile applications. 

We may disclose or otherwise make available personal information about you to service providers that help with the operation of our mobile applications. These providers may collect device-specific information, such as a unique device identifier, when you use our website or one of our mobile applications. This information will not be associated in any way with your account at ASDA or any personal information that identifies who you are. The device identifier is used to improve services within our mobile applications such as barcode scanners or speech recognition. We require our service providers to keep your information secure. In addition, our service providers may not use or disclose personal information for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf. We may also work with analytics companies to help us understand how our mobile applications are being used, such as the frequency and duration of usage. To protect the anonymity of this information, we use an encryption technology to help ensure that these third parties can't identify you personally based on information they collect from our mobile applications or your use of them. These analytics providers may also have access to your device-specific information such as a unique device identifier. This information will not be associated in any way with your account at ASDA or any personal information that identifies who you are, and we require these service providers to keep your information secure. 

There are multiple options for users of our mobile applications to opt-out of the collection and of your location information: 

Opt-out of all information collection by uninstalling our mobile applications – You can stop all collection of information by our mobile applications easily by uninstalling the mobile applications. You may use the standard uninstall processes available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. 

Un-install - You can stop all collection of information by our mobile applications easily by uninstalling mobile applications. You may use the standard uninstall processes available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. Note: If you uninstall the mobile application from your device, the ASDA unique identifier associated with your device will continue to be stored. If you re-install the application on the same device, ASDA will be able to re-associate this identifier to your previous transactions. 

Adjust permissions - You may at any time opt-out from further allowing us to have access to your location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device. 

## Links

Our website may contain links to let you to visit other websites of interest easily. Once you have used these links to leave our website, you should be aware that we do not have any control over that other website. As such we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting these websites, and they are not governed by this Privacy Policy. ASDA is not responsible for any products and/or services featured on any third party website. You should exercise caution and look at the Privacy Policy applicable to the website in question. 

## Notification of Changes to This Policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post these changes on this website so you know what information we collect and how we use it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will tell you. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. 

## Feedback

We want to make sure we're giving you the information about privacy and security that you want - let us know what you think. If you have any feedback, questions or concerns, please email us at [dataprotection@asda.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@asda.co.uk). 

## ASDA group of companies:

**Asda Stores Limited**   
Asda House   
South Bank   
Great Wilson Street   
Leeds   
LS11 5AD   
Registered in England & Wales, company No. 00464777   
ICO registration no: Z7545987   
FCA No. 407914   
VAT No. GB 362 0127 92 

**Asda Financial Services Limited**   
Asda House Southbank   
Great Wilson Street   
Leeds   
West Yorkshire   
LS11 5AD   
Registered in England & Wales, company No. 04562707   
ICO registration no: Z1392501   
FCA No. 230174
